<resources>
    <string name="app_name">first aid kit</string>
    <string name="cpr">1. Position your hand (below)\nMake sure the patient is lying on his back on a firm surface. Kneel beside him and place the heel of your hand on the center of the chest.\n
    2. Interlock fingers (below)\n
    Keeping your arms straight, cover the first hand with the heel of your other hand and interlock the fingers of both hands together. Keep your fingers raised so they do not touch the patient’s chest or rib cage.\n
    3. Give chest compressions (below)\n
    Lean forward so that your shoulders are directly over the patient’s chest and press down on the chest about two inches. Release the pressure, but not your hands, and let the chest come back up.\n
    5. Give rescue breaths (below)\n
    Pinch the nostrils closed with the hand that was on the forehead and support the patient’s chin with your other hand. Take a normal breath, put your mouth over the patient’s, and blow until you can see his chest rise.\n
    6. Watch chest fall\n
    Remove your mouth from the patient’s and look along the chest, watching the chest fall. Repeat steps five and six once. Make sure your child memorizes these CPR steps</string>
    <string name="bites">Treatment for minor reactions::\n
    If you can, remove the stinger as soon as possible, such as by scraping it off with a fingernail.\n
        Wash the sting area with soap and water.
        Apply a cold compress.\n\n
        Treatment for moderate reactions::\n
        If you can, remove the stinger as soon as possible, such as by scraping it off with a fingernail.
        Donot try to remove the stinger below the skin surface.
        A stinger may not be present, as only bees leave their stingers. Other stinging insects, such as wasps, do not.\n
        Wash the affected area with soap and water.\n
        Apply a cold compress.\n
        Take an over-the-counter pain reliever as needed. You might try ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others) to help ease discomfort.\n
        If the sting is on an arm or leg, elevate it.\n
        Apply hydrocortisone cream or calamine lotion to ease redness, itching or swelling.\n
        If itching or swelling is bothersome, take an oral antihistamine that contains diphenhydramine (Benadryl) or chlorpheniramine.\n
        Avoid scratching the sting area. This will worsen itching and swelling and increase your risk of infection.

    </string>

    <string name="heartattack">Someone having a heart attack may experience any or all of the following:\n
> Uncomfortable pressure, fullness or squeezing pain in the center of the chest\n
> Discomfort or pain spreading beyond the chest to the shoulders, back, neck, jaw, teeth, or one or both arms, or occasionally upper abdomen\n
> Shortness of breath\n
> Lightheadedness, dizziness, fainting\n
> Sweating\n
> Nausea\n\n

        First Aid:\n
If you think someone is having a heart attack:\n

> Have the person sit down, rest, and try to keep calm.\n
> Loosen any tight clothing.\n
> Ask if the person takes any chest pain medicine, such as nitroglycerin, for a known heart condition, and help them take it.\n
> If the pain does not go away promptly with rest or within 3 minutes of taking nitroglycerin, call for emergency medical help.\n
> If the person is unconscious and unresponsive, call 911 or the local emergency number, then begin CPR.\n
> If an infant or child is unconscious and unresponsive, perform 1 minute of CPR, then call 911 or the local emergency number.\n\n
   Do Not:\n
> DO NOT leave the person alone except to call for help, if necessary.\n
> DO NOT allow the person to deny the symptoms and convince you not to call for emergency help.\n
> DO NOT wait to see if the symptoms go away.\n
> DO NOT give the person anything by mouth unless a heart medicine (such as nitroglycerin) has been prescribed.\n
        </string>
    <string name="heatcold">HEAT AND COLD TREATMENT:\n
        Heat and Cold exhaustion signs and symptoms include:\n

> Cool, moist skin with goose bumps when in the heat\n
> Heavy sweating\n
> Faintness\n
> Dizziness\n
> Fatigue\n
> Weak, rapid pulse\n
> Low blood pressure upon standing\n
> Muscle cramps\n
> Nausea\n
> Headache\n\n
        If you suspect heat exhaustion::\n
Untreated, heat exhaustion can lead to heatstroke, which is a life-threatening condition. If you suspect heat exhaustion, take these steps immediately:\n

> Move the person out of the heat and into a shady or air-conditioned place.\n
> Lay the person down and elevate the legs and feet slightly.\n
> Remove tight or heavy clothing.\n
> Have the person drink cool water or other nonalcoholic beverage without caffeine.\n
> Cool the person by spraying or sponging with cool water and fanning.\n
> Monitor the person carefully.\n
Contact a doctor if signs or symptoms worsen or if they don't improve within one hour.

    </string>


    <string name="poison">When to suspect poisoning:\n
Poisoning signs and symptoms can mimic other conditions, such as seizure, alcohol intoxication, stroke and insulin reaction. Signs and symptoms of poisoning may include:\n

> Burns or redness around the mouth and lips\n
> Breath that smells like chemicals, such as gasoline or paint thinner\n
> Vomiting\n
> Difficulty breathing\n
> Drowsiness\n
> Confusion or other altered mental status\n
 If you suspect poisoning, be alert for clues such as empty pill bottles or packages, scattered pills, and burns, stains and odors on the person or nearby objects. With a child, consider the possibility that he or she may have applied medicated patches or swallowed a button battery.\n\n
    What to do while waiting for help?\n
Take the following actions until help arrives:\n

> Swallowed poison. Remove anything remaining in the person\'s mouth. If the suspected poison is a household cleaner or other chemical, read the container's label and follow instructions for accidental poisoning.\n
> Poison on the skin. Remove any contaminated clothing using gloves. Rinse the skin for 15 to 20 minutes in a shower or with a hose.\n
> Poison in the eye. Gently flush the eye with cool or lukewarm water for 20 minutes or until help arrives.\n
> Inhaled poison. Get the person into fresh air as soon as possible.\n
> If the person vomits, turn his or her head to the side to prevent choking.\n
> Begin CPR if the person shows no signs of life, such as moving, breathing or coughing.\n
> Have somebody gather pill bottles, packages or containers with labels, and any other information about the poison to send along with the ambulance team.   \n

    </string>

    <string name="nosebleed">Nosebleeds are common. Most often they are a nuisance and not a true medical problem. But they can be both.\n
        Nosebleed care:\n
        1. Stop the Bleeding:\n
> Have the person sit up straight and lean forward slightly. Don\'t have the person lie down or tilt the head backward.\n
> With thumb and index finger, firmly pinch the nose just below the bone up against the face.\n
> Apply pressure for 5 minutes. Time yourself with a clock.\n
> If bleeding continues after 5 minutes, repeat the process.\n
        2. Medical Treatment:\n
The healthcare provider may use specialized cotton material, insert a balloon in the nose, or use a special electrical tool to cauterize the blood vessels.\n
3. Follow Up:\n
> Broken noses often are not fixed immediately. The healthcare provider will refer the person to a specialist for a consultation once the swelling goes down.\n
> The person should avoid strenuous activity; bending over; and blowing, rubbing, or picking the nose until it heals.\n
> The nostrils should be kept moist with a water-based lubricant or by increasing the humidity in the home.\n


        </string>

</resources>
