<resources>
    <string name="app_name">first aid kit</string>
    <string name="cpr">1. Position your hand (below)\nMake sure the patient is lying on his back on a firm surface. Kneel beside him and place the heel of your hand on the center of the chest.\n
    2. Interlock fingers (below)\n
    Keeping your arms straight, cover the first hand with the heel of your other hand and interlock the fingers of both hands together. Keep your fingers raised so they do not touch the patient’s chest or rib cage.\n
    3. Give chest compressions (below)\n
    Lean forward so that your shoulders are directly over the patient’s chest and press down on the chest about two inches. Release the pressure, but not your hands, and let the chest come back up.\n
    5. Give rescue breaths (below)\n
    Pinch the nostrils closed with the hand that was on the forehead and support the patient’s chin with your other hand. Take a normal breath, put your mouth over the patient’s, and blow until you can see his chest rise.\n
    6. Watch chest fall\n
    Remove your mouth from the patient’s and look along the chest, watching the chest fall. Repeat steps five and six once. Make sure your child memorizes these CPR steps</string>
    <string name="bites">Treatment for minor reactions::\n
    If you can, remove the stinger as soon as possible, such as by scraping it off with a fingernail.\n
        Wash the sting area with soap and water.
        Apply a cold compress.\n\n
        Treatment for moderate reactions::\n
        If you can, remove the stinger as soon as possible, such as by scraping it off with a fingernail.
        Donot try to remove the stinger below the skin surface.
        A stinger may not be present, as only bees leave their stingers. Other stinging insects, such as wasps, do not.\n
        Wash the affected area with soap and water.\n
        Apply a cold compress.\n
        Take an over-the-counter pain reliever as needed. You might try ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others) to help ease discomfort.\n
        If the sting is on an arm or leg, elevate it.\n
        Apply hydrocortisone cream or calamine lotion to ease redness, itching or swelling.\n
        If itching or swelling is bothersome, take an oral antihistamine that contains diphenhydramine (Benadryl) or chlorpheniramine.\n
        Avoid scratching the sting area. This will worsen itching and swelling and increase your risk of infection.

    </string>

</resources>
